

Luka Tsiklauri

PHP Full-Stack Developer



Get in Touch with info.tsiklauri@gmail.com
LinkedIn
Telegram

ABOUT ME

A software developer with over 7 years of experience, ready to lead and take a full responsibility in developing your software product. always honest, always transparent. The 3 key that leads me to create successful software are

- 1. Discipline
- 2. Passion for success
- 3. The result

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- · Strong analytical & problem solving skills
- Lean, Agile, Scrum and Kanban frameworks
- · Strategic thinking and planning skills

CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate in <u>Cyber security</u>
 Business & Technology University
 2021

Certificate in <u>Business & Finances</u>
Georgian National University
2020

Certificate in <u>Web Development</u>
 Intellect center
 2017

WORK HISTORY

Megainsight SIA - Full-Stack Developer

Mar 2023 - Sep 2024

Senior PHP/Vue developer

I primarily worked on optimizing API requests, identifying bottlenecks, creating queue systems for handling millions of user messages, indexing tables, analyzing queries (using EXPLAIN), partitions, and normalization. In the team, we used the Laravel framework. I adhered to <u>PSR-12</u> standards, strict_types, and documented the code.

I also participated in the Keeptip startup, where I developed API endpoints, integrated payment systems like **Stripe** and **Revolut**, and worked on the architecture.

SIDES GmbH - Back-End Developer

Mar 2022 - Feb 2023

Senior PHP developer

I've been managing development team, collaborating with stakeholders and developing POS and payment systems.

MYGE - Back-End Developer

Feb 2019 - Jan 2022

PHP developer

I was developing the largest web-platform in Georgia <u>mymarket.ge</u> by implementing a complex software system and optmizing website for millions of users.

Freelancer Full-Stack Developer

Jan 2017 - NOW Full-Stack Developer

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Georgian Technical University

IT

2020 - 2022

Moscow Institute of Physic & Technology Algorithms & Data structures

2020

Intellect Center

Web development courses

2016-2017

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript ¡Query, React]s, Vue]s
- Dart Flutter

Back-End

- PHP, Symfony **7.x**, Laravel **5.1 11.x**
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQL, NoSQL
- AWS, GCP, Firebase, Cloud microservices
- RabbitMQ, Kafka, Sockets
- Redis, memcached
- Docker, kubernetes
- ClickHouse

General

- Algorithms & Data Structures
- Big C
- OOP SOLID principles + 24 Design patterns
- Clean Architecture & Clean code by Robert Martin

Other

- KISS, SOLID, DRY methodologies
- Concurrent, Reactive, Functional programming
- REST/SOAP API, TCP/IP Sockets
- MVC, MVVM, Lifting State
- TDD, BDD approaches
- GIT, Jira, Codemagic, CI/CD, Zoho
- A/B testing + User behavior analytic + Crash logging

TECHNICAL FOCUS

- PHP 8.3 PSR-12 strict types.
- Performance optimization, Garbage collection, Queue management, Caching, Patterns.
- · Load balancing, Proxy servers, Cloud services.
- SQL, Query optimization, EXPLAIN, Indexing, Partitions, Procedures.
- Payment gateways, 3rd party API integration HTTP/s TCP/IP
- · Bottlenecks, Code analyzing.